In software engineering,
design patterns are a general and
reusable solution to common problems that
occur in a particular context
when designing
applications.  These are not a
final solution that is then transformed into
source code, but rather a description or
template that you can use at
any given time.
[Music]
Hello world and welcome to this video.
Design patterns are the
formalization of good practices that a
software engineer can use
to solve common problems.  In
object-oriented programming,
design patterns typically
show relationships and interactions
among different objects and classes,
although patterns that imply
mutability are not useful when
using a strict functional paradigm
.  Some patterns might
even be classified as unnecessary or
useless depending on the paradigm,
language, or libraries we are
using, since these might already have
specific solutions to
solve those problems.  In this video,
we'll look at six
design patterns, but don't think of
them as silver bullets.
Using any of these patterns could
be a terrible idea depending on your
context.  But before I tell you about the
six design patterns and what problems
they solve, I have to tell you that
the like button just wrote
spaghetti code.  And this is a terrible
practice in software development,
so to teach that bastard
not to keep writing
spaghetti code, you have to hit him an
even number of times until he turns blue.
When the like button turns
blue, he'll have learned that he shouldn't
continue writing spaghetti code.
And if you hit the like button, you'll make
our development community
a whole lot better, because the like button will
have been directed toward writing
better quality code.  And since that
damn thing is in blue, let's continue with
our video.  In
software engineering, the Singleton pattern restricts
the instantiation of a class to only a
single instance.  This is useful when you
need only one instance of a
class to coordinate actions
between different systems.  If your system
only has one database, singleton.
If you have only one API, singleton.  If
you need to connect to a service
like AWS and only one instance of
it, Singleton.  Depending on the
language, you may not need to
implement a singleton class.  In
Node JS you can implement an object
literal and export it.  This will behave
just like a singleton, since the
Node engine has implemented a cache with
the exported variables, so it
will always be the same.  But in case of
Java, which has a
stricter implementation, it should be implemented as
follows.  First the class is created
.  Then you define a property
called Singleton, which will hold the
instance we created.  We then define
a constructor called Singleton.  That
constructor will be responsible for building the
object that we will need in the
future.  Then we create a method called
get instance, which will be responsible for
returning the instance of our
singleton.  In object-oriented programming
, the decorator pattern is a
pattern that allows you to add
functionality to an object without altering
the behavior of other
object instances of the same class.  It solves the
problem of adding or removing
responsibilities to an object at
runtime and is a flexible alternative to
subclassing.  And a
Java implementation would look something like this.  If we're
going to sell coffee, we'll need to
know its price and we'll also
need to know its ingredients. Of
course, coffee has coffee, but we
might also want to sell coffee with
milk.  And instead of creating a new
class and reimplementing the methods, it would
be better to take the rate that already exists
and pass it through the constructor to a
milk class.  This class creates methods with the
same names, but calls
the methods of the coffee object first.  And when
someone asks for the price, we add the
value of the milk.  And when someone
requests ingredients, we
also add milk as an ingredient.
In software engineering, the
mediator pattern defines an object, which
encapsulates how other objects will
interact.  This pattern is considered a
behavioral pattern, as it can
alter how the application runs.
A mediator pattern in JavaScript is defined
as follows.  First,
we define an ifi, which stands for
immediate invoked expression.  To this we
add a variable, which will contain
the events that can be dispatched or
listened to.  Next, we create a function
called subscribe.  This will be responsible for
receiving the event and also the function
that will be executed.  This must be
recorded in our
events variable.  Next we create a function
called dispatch.  This will receive the
event being dispatched and also
the data that will be passed as an argument
to the function we will subscribe to.  This
function will go through all the events that
are registered and if it finds
one or more than one, it will execute the
functions and pass the data to each
of them.  Then we return these
functions and with that we have built
our mediator.  The difference between a
mediator and an observer is that the
mediator requires a separate object to
handle communications
between all objects, while the
observer modifies the object it is supposed to
listen to.  The observing pattern does not
have this intermediary.  Redux
implements the mediator pattern.  In
software engineering, the
adapter pattern allows an object that is not
designed to work with an
interface to be modified so that it
can work with it.  In Python
we can define an adapter pattern by
creating two classes.  First, we create an
Android class and an iPhone class.
Android recharges with USB and iPhone
recharges with Lightning.  I can create a
charger class that receives the phone
that needs to be charged, but this
would only work with USB.  So in order for
the iPhone to be able to charge, I can create
an iPhone adapter class that receives the
iPhone and when its method
to charge the phone with USB is called,
it charges it with Lightning.  This
way, this adapted iPhone could be
used with the Android charger.
The MBC pattern, also known as
Model View Controller, is
commonly used to develop
user interfaces by dividing the logic into three
interconnected elements.  The model,
which contains the logic of your
application, will be responsible for calling the
different data and contains the
business rules.  The view is the
visual representation of the data being collected.
This is what the user and
controller will see.  It is responsible for receiving the
data, transforming it into something useful for
the model, receiving the data from the model and
then constructing the response for the
user.  An example of MBC can be
easily seen in Node js with Express, where
we create an endpoint responsible for receiving
requests from our user.  With
that request we will search for the data
that he needs.  We then return
this data to the user and of course
handle exceptions if
they exist.  If there is an HTML,
we render it with the data
we collected, but in this case
we return the data as if it were a
Rest API, so our view in
quotes in this case is a Jason.  The
Flux pattern was developed by
Facebook a few years ago in response
to existing patterns and it
complements the functionality of the
library they also created.
called React Flux.  It is also a
framework with the same name, but the
important thing about this pattern, unlike
the MBC, is that it is a
circular cycle where the user triggers
an event from the view.  This performs
some actions that then update the
state of our application and after
the state has been updated, our
application renders again,
thus updating the view.
Hopefully, after watching this
video, you'll get a sense of the
patterns that exist, but don't think
these are the best or
silver bullets.  These are simply
tools that you can add
to your arsenal.  And if you want to learn more
about more design patterns
out there,
I have a course on design patterns in the description of this video.
We look at some of these and many
other patterns that you can use in your
everyday life.  And of course, when you
're studying, you can do so by
listening to my music, as it helps
improve concentration and will make
your studies and work more
productive.  And this was this week's video
.  If you liked it, remember to hit
that damn like button a lot.
Remember, he wrote spaghetti code.  If
you loved it, please consider subscribing to this
channel.  Leave me a comment below
about what other types of videos you'd like
me to make.  And if you'd like to delve deeper
into a subject,
you'll of course also find links
to all my courses below.  Until
next time and bye world.
[Music]